1. ABOUT THE DATASET

1.1. Title of Dataset: Characterization of the Firm-Firm Public Procurement Co-Bidding Network from the State of Ceará (Brazil) Municipalities

1.2. Author Information
	A. First Author
		Name: Marcos S. Lyra
		Institution: Tribunal de Contas do Estado do Ceará
		Address: Rua Sena Madureira, 1047 - CEP: 60055-080 – 
		         Fortaleza/CE - Brazil
		Email: marcos.lyra@tce.ce.gov.br

	B. Principal Investigator
		Name: Flávio L. Pinheiro
		Institution: Nova Information Management School
		Address: Campus de Campolide, 1070-312 Lisboa
		Email: fpinheiro@isegi.unl.pt

1.3. Date of data collection: 2020-10-15 
1.4. Geographic location of data collection: Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil 
1.5. Information about funding sources that supported the data collection: The TCE-CE freely provided all the data. It maintains a database of all bidding processes over the years from the 184 municipalities of the state of Ceará.
1.6. Description: The data shared in this repository was compiled by Tribunal de Contas do Estado do Ceará (TCE-CE). It contains information on the public tender process from 184 municipalities of Ceará. In particular, it identifies which firms made a bid to which tender. The dataset is partially available in an open format on the institution's website (https://api.tce.ce.gov.br/). The data made available for the scientific research does not contain the bidding values.  Names of firms and municipalities have been anonymized. 
1.7. Related publication: We use this Data set to characterize the Firm-Firm co-bidding network formed by firms' participation in the public tender process. The result of analyzing this Dataset constitute the the basis of a scientific manuscript that is currently under review. 

2. TERMS OF USE
The use of this dataset has no restrictions.

3. PROJECT AND FUNDING INFORMATION
NA

4. CONTENTS
File listing: The data set is composed of 3 files, Bipartite Bid Data.csv, Tender Data.csv, and Firm Data.csv
Bipartite Bid Data.csv – consists of Bids referring to 184 municipalities in the state of Ceará (Brazil) between the years 2015 to 2019,
containing 196,608 rows of information (excluding header) corresponding to the Bids or Edges that each of the 45,502 Firms bid on 84,835 Tenders.
The file consists of five columns:
•	MUNICIPALITY - Anonymized code of the 184 Municipalities of Ceará issuing the 84,835 Tenders.
•	TENDER - Anonymized code of the 84,835 Tenders issued by the 184 municipalities of Ceara between 2015 and 2019. 
•	FIRM - Anonymous code representing the 45,502 Bidders (Firms) who bid on the Tenders in which they participated. 
•	WINNER - logical value that indicates whether the Firm that bid on the Tender was successful or not. Number 1 represents victory, and number 0 represents defeat. 
•	YEAR – indicates the year in which each of the 196,608 bids was accomplished by the 45,502 Firms in each of the 84,835 Tenders.

To assemble the Tender Data and Firm Data files, we filtered the data. We discarded all firms that did not bid at least once during each year of analysis, remaining with the core of active firms while removing firms with sporadic activity.  The final working data set included 1,906 firms, which account for 72,078 bids to 39,523 tenders

Tender Data.csv – it has 39,523 rows corresponding to information only about the Tenders with 4 columns:
•	MUNICIPALITY – Anonymized code of the 184 Municipalities of Ceará issuing the 39,523 Tenders.
•	REGION – Name of the regions to which each municipality belongs. Grouping of the municipalities of Ceará in 7 mesoregions: CENTRO SUL, JAGUARIBE, METROPOLITANA, NOROESTE, NORTE, SERTAO, SUL
•	TENDER – Anonymized code of the 39,523 filtered Tenders.
•	TYPE – Informs, among 12 kinds, the type of object being bid: SERVICES, FOOD, CONSUMABLES HEALTH, ASSETS, FUEL, CONSUMABLES GENERAL, EVENT, CONSUMABLES EDUCATION, CONSTRUCTION, TRANSPORTATION, TENANCY, ADVERTISEMENT.

Firm Data.csv – it has 1,906 rows corresponding to information only about the Firms with 13 columns:
•	FIRM – Anonymous code representing the 1,906 filtered Bidders (Firms) who bid on the Tenders in which they participated.
•	SERVICES TENDERS -  Number of SERVICES objects that the firm has bid
•	FOOD TENDERS -  Number of FOOD objects that the firm has bid
•	CONSUMABLES HEALTH TENDERS -  Number of CONSUMABLES HEALTH objects that the firm has bid
•	ASSETS TENDERS - Number of ASSETS objects that the firm has bid
•	FUEL TENDERS - Number of FUEL objects that the firm has bid
•	CONSUMABLES GENERAL TENDERS - Number of CONSUMABLES GENERAL objects that the firm has bid
•	EVENT TENDERS - Number of EVENT objects that the firm has bid
•	CONSUMABLES EDUCATION TENDERS - Number of CONSUMABLES EDUCATION objects that the firm has bid
•	CONSTRUCTION TENDERS - Number of CONSTRUCTION objects that the firm has bid
•	TRANSPORTATION TENDERS - Number of TRANSPORTATION objects that the firm has bid
•	TENANCY TENDERS - Number of TENANCY objects that the firm has bid
•	ADVERTISEMENT TENDERS - Number of ADVERTISEMENT objects that the firm has bid

